Today we will talk about a new product
.  ICICI
Lombard and ICICI Prudential have come
together to introduce a product that
covers health insurance and life insurance in a single product
.  First,
let's understand what an eye shield is.
Term life insurance from ICICI Prudential
and
health insurance from IICI Lombard are covered under the I Shield plan
.  These dual benefits
cover hospitalization expenses
and provide
financial support to the family in the event of an unexpected death
.  There are many benefits to taking this plan
.  There are no First One Multiple
Insurance Policy Copies.  There is a single policy copy for health
insurance and life insurance
.  Second one is smooth on-boarding
process, single proposal form, single
medical checkup and premium payment,
third one is easy renewal and tracking with single payment
.
Fourth One Sama Insure health cover range is
5 lakhs to 20 lakhs and life cover is 50
lakhs to 1 crore. Fifth One This plan can
be taken by anyone between the ages of 18 to 65 years.  There is also a tax benefit
in this.
You can get income tax benefits under 80C and 80D.  Sixth One
Anywhere Cashless You
can get cashless treatment at any hospital of your choice.  All you need to do is
submit a request on the ILTC app 24 hours before you want to be admitted
.  Seventh One: This policy provides life cover
from 85 to 95 years
.  Eight One has
special premium rates for non-tobacco users.
Now let's find out
what is covered and what is not covered in the iShield Combi policy.
That is, inclusions and
exclusions. First, let's
look at what is covered in health insurance.   The
first inpatient hospitalization
will be covered up to a certain amount.  This means that if you have a
health issue and need to be hospitalized for
at least 24 hours, that
treatment will be covered up to some extent
.  Second,
some day care treatments
are covered even if you are in the hospital for less than 24 hours.  Example Cataract
Treatment Chemotherapy
Dialysis and Angiography etc.
Third One Pre and Post
Hospitalization Expenses In case of
hospitalization, any expenses related to hospitalization for
60 days before admission and 180 days after discharge will
also be covered
.  Fourth One Domestic Air
Ambulance expenses
will be covered up to some extent.  Fifth One
will cover ambulance service expenses up to a maximum of 10,000.  Sixth
One Home Care Treatment
also
covers the cost of treatment at home instead of being admitted to a hospital, as advised by the doctor.  Seventh One Restore
Benefit Restore benefit means that
you
can use up to 100% of the sum assured as an extra in this policy if, for example, you are admitted to the hospital or if you are exhausted.
Eight One Guaranteed Cumulative Bonus
Cumulative bonus means that if no
claim is made within one year, for example, an
extra 20% sum will be added in the next year's renewal time
.  It will
add up to a maximum of 100%.
Now let's look at exclusions in health coverage
.  You can avail cashless or reimbursement
only after 30 days of taking out the First One policy
.  In case of any accidental
cases, you can get cashless or reimbursement from the first day
.  Second, some diseases are
not covered for the first two years.
Pre-existing
diseases like cataract, hernia, stone in the urinary system, etc. are covered only after two years
.  Now let's see
what is covered in term life insurance
.  First one is unexpected death
benefit, second one is accidental death
benefit, third one is waiver of future
premiums, i.e. in case of
permanent disability in any accidental cases, there is
no need to pay future premium.  The fourth one is the Critical Illness
Benefit, which
covers 34 critical illnesses
.
Let's look at term life coverage exclusions.  First one is attempted suicide or
self-inflicted injuries
accidental under the influence of any
narcotic etc. Now let us
look at permanent exclusion.  War,
Civil War, Treatment taken outside the
country, Any expenses arising out
of the domiciliary treatment,
etc. Now let's see how to select the sum insured for life insurance
as well as health insurance
.   While the
first option life coverage is 50 lockz, the
health cover can be taken for 5 lockz
or 10 lockz
.  When taking the second option life cover of 1
crore, you
can select health cover of 10 lakhs or 20 lakhs.
Let's look at an example of how this policy works.  Let's say a
person named Raju took out a health cover of 20 locks at the age of 35
and a life cover of 1 crore valid up to the
age of 85
.  Raju is believed to have been
admitted to the hospital due to health issues when he was 47 and
received a cashless 10-lock loan.
Similarly, if the
king dies unexpectedly at the age of 75, an
amount of Rs 1 crore will go to his nominee.
Finally, it is a good idea to
understand the policy terms and conditions well, no matter what policy you choose to take
.  If you like this video, like,
share and
subscribe to this channel for more videos.